<Claude Müller/>

#Full Stack Software Developer

Hard-working, enthusiastic, self-made coder who has learned various programming languages, which he uses to create custom software solutions. Webapps, websites, APIs, Arduino projects and video games are just some of the projects he's worked on. Enjoys contemplating problems and the way things work, how to fix or improve upon them, then takes great pleasure in building a creative and robust solution. Loves to constantly learn and acquire any skill needed through dedication and self-application.

Work History

2018/03 - Current

Freelance Full Stack Software Developer

dxt.rs - Remote

- Develop websites, APIs and systems using: HTML; CSS; PHP (Laravel, PyroCMS, CakePHP, CodeIgniter, WordPress, vanilla); JavaScript & TypeScript (Angular, AngularJS, jQuery, Meteor); Node.js; Ionic & PhoneGap;
- Linux server administration (Ubuntu, CentOS, Debian).
- MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB databases.



2019/04 - 2020/03

Full Stack Developer Consultant

Team Extension - Bucharest (Remote)

- Wrote server-side and client-side code for Laravel and PyroCMS projects using PHP (Laravel), HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Part of team that built Laravel-based CRM system as well as custom
 PyroCMS website a company in energy management.
- Used Git, Jira, CircleCl.



2019/01 - 2020/01

PHP and JavaScript Developer

Crayon - Johannesburg, Gauteng (Remote)

- Rewrote recruitment webapp into full Laravel and JavaScript-based solution that caters to 37000+ users.
- Extended MVP to include various features including: integration with payment partner; webcam integration; custom filtering.
- Linux (CentOS) VPS administration.
- Used Git, Asana.



Contact

E-mail ☑

claude@dxt.rs

LinkedIn In

LinkedIn Profile

Portfolio

https://claudemuller.io

Github 🗊

https://github.com/claudemuller

Blog 🖹

Unschooled Life

Skills



Other Tech

C, C++, Java, Perl, Shell Scripting, Objective-C, Assembly, Node.js, PHPUnit, Jasmine, SQLite, MongoDB, Electron, Ionic, PhoneGap, PixiJS, SDL, Cocos2D, Arduino

Derivco - La Lucia, KwaZulu-Natal

- Maintained and extended global online Bingo app servicing millions of players.
- Wrote custom TypeScript and JavaScript Angular modules.
- Integrated with .NET back-end via protocol buffers.
- Extended custom integration with PixiJS WebGL/Canvas renderer.
- Wrote integration and unit tests with Jasmine.
- Used SVN, Git, TFS.



2015/01 - 2016/09

CTO and Chief Software Developer

Media Rocket Studio - Rivonia, Gauteng

- Architected customer front-end and back-end solutions.
- Wrote APIs and web systems with front-end in PHP (WordPress, Laravel) and JavaScript (AngularJS, jQuery) and back-end in PHP & JavaScript (Laravel, Node.js).
- Mobile apps with Ionic and PhoneGap.
- MySQL and MongoDB databases.
- Linux administration (Ubuntu).
- Used Git



2013/08 - 2014/12

Full Stack Web Developer

Flint Studio - Morningside, Gauteng

- Develop systems and integrations using PHP (Laravel, CakePHP and vanilla).
- Develop custom themes and websites using PHP and WordPress.
- Work closely with designers to implement custom designs as per client spec.



2012/07 - 2013/07

Full Stack PHP and JavaScript Developer

Team Extension - Faerie Glen, Gauteng

- Rewrote internal and client-facing web systems from Perl into PHP (Codelgniter) and JavaScript.
- Built mobile app for Android (native), iOS (native) and BlackBerry (PhoneGap).
- Built email campaign management utilities in Python.
- Linux administration (CentOS).



2010/01 - 2012/06

Owner/Web Designer/Web Developer

dragonFli designs - Benoni, Gauteng

• Built websites and systems for various clients in PHP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS from scratch.

• Maintained and installed networks, workstations, servers and backup solutions.



Education

Tertiary

2022 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

University Of The People - Pasadena (Distance)

2022 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Open Source Society University – The Internet (Distance)

2004 A+ Hardware and Software

CTU Training Solutions

Certificates

2020/04 <u>Python for Everybody Specialization</u>

Coursera

2020/04 <u>Capstone: Retrieving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python</u>

Coursera

2020/04 <u>Python for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)</u>

Coursera

2020/04 Python Data Structures *

Coursera

2020/04 <u>Using Databases with Python</u>

Coursera

2020/04 <u>Using Python to Access Web Data</u>

Coursera

2020/04 <u>Introduction to Game Development</u>

Coursera

2019/06 Fundamentals of 2D Game Engines with C++ and Lua *

Udemy

2017/09 How to Program Games: Tile Classics in JS for HTML5 Canvas *

Udemy